<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Karan</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Karan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:46:20 +0545</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>F5 BIG-IP &#43; Wazuh: Getting Logs Working After 18 Months</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025/11/f5-big-ip--wazuh-getting-logs-working-after-18-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:46:20 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025/11/f5-big-ip--wazuh-getting-logs-working-after-18-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When hope was almost gone, I decided to give the F5–Wazuh integration one more try.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Its already been eighteen months since I first had the failure trying integrate it, tried more than 50 times, had nearly convinced me these two were never going to get along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;F5 BIG-IP is a good of a solutions when it comes to Web Application Firewall and Load Balancing tasks. I’ve been working with it for over half and a year now — it does its job quite well, protecting applications through real time traffic inspection and respective response enforcement. But it comes with a very real limit when it comes to local log storage at least in this series of F5 WAF which is claimed to be fixed in newer product series. On virtual editions, it caps at 3 million records or 2 GB of database space; on physical systems, it goes to 5 GB.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Essential HTTP Routing Patterns</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2025/04/three-essential-http-routing-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 12:13:30 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2025/04/three-essential-http-routing-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HTTP routing is a fundamental concept in web development that determines how web applications handle and direct incoming requests. Let&amp;rsquo;s go through the three primary routing patterns that every web developer should understand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-host-based-routing&#34;&gt;1. Host-Based Routing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Host-based routing, also known as VHOST (Virtual Host) routing, is a pattern where multiple domain names point to the same server or endpoint. This approach is particularly useful for managing multiple services under different domains while utilizing the same infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
